=Spring Fever= =Episode 13=
=حمى الربيع= =الحلقة 13=
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
I came too late.
لقد جئت متأخرا جدا.
It's not your fault.
إنه ليس خطؤك.
It's them.
إنهم هم.
You've also risked your life
لقد خاطرت بحياتك أيضًا
to get here.
للوصول إلى هنا.
Uncle, here's some candy for you.
عمي، هنا بعض الحلوى لك.
Thank you, Lady Jin.
شكرا لك، سيدة جين.
Jin.
إحساس.
Mother, look. This uncle made me a toy ox.
أمي، انظري. هذا العم صنع لي ثورًا لعبة.
So pretty. Did you thank him?
كم هو جميل. هل شكرته؟
You spend money on her every time.
أنت تنفق المال عليها في كل مرة.
No need to bring gifts next time.
لا داعي لإحضار الهدايا في المرة القادمة.
Just a simple craft from the mountains.
مجرد حرفة بسيطة من الجبال.
As long as Lady Jin likes it.
طالما أن السيدة جين تحب ذلك.
I'm sorry about your brother.
أنا آسف بشأن أخيك.
When we return,
عندما نعود،
I'll have Gao Fu retrieve his remains.
سأطلب من جاو فو استعادة رفاته.
I'll give him a proper burial.
سأعطيه دفنًا لائقًا.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
(Mu, wait here for me.)
(مو انتظرني هنا.)
Can you accompany me to the Baiyi Alley textile shop?
هل يمكنك مرافقتي إلى متجر النسيج في Baiyi Alley؟
Okay.
تمام.
(Baiyi Alley textile shop)
(متجر نسيج بايي آلي)
The letter.
الرسالة.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
The letter's inside.
الرسالة بالداخل.
The letter's inside!
الرسالة بالداخل!
(Duting Station)
(محطة دوتينغ)
Mu.
في.
Why are you so reckless?
لماذا أنت متهور هكذا؟
You didn't ask anything,
لم تسأل شيئا
and didn't know my plan,
ولم يعرف خطتي،
yet you charged in anyway.
ولكنك قمت بالشحن على أية حال.
Are you trying to get yourself killed?
هل تحاول أن تقتل نفسك؟
Lord Shen is alive and well.
اللورد شين على قيد الحياة وبصحة جيدة.
Don't jinx him, Lady Ye.
لا تجلبي له النحس، سيدتي يي.
He's breathing, right?
إنه يتنفس، أليس كذلك؟
My lord,
سيدي،
was anything left in Baiyi Alley textile shop
هل بقي شيء في متجر النسيج في زقاق بايي؟
yesterday?
أمس؟
When I arrived,
عندما وصلت،
the shop had collapsed.
لقد انهار المتجر.
Most items inside were burnt to ash.
احترقت معظم العناصر الموجودة بالداخل وتحولت إلى رماد.
Nothing remained?
لم يبقى شيء؟
I searched the ruins thoroughly,
لقد بحثت في الآثار جيدا،
but found nothing.
ولكن لم أجد شيئا.
Were nearby households affected?
هل تأثرت الأسر القريبة؟
Several houses next to it were completely burned.
احترقت عدة منازل مجاورة له بشكل كامل.
Over ten people injured,
أصيب أكثر من عشرة أشخاص،
three fatalities.
ثلاث وفيات.
Lady Ye, you...
سيدة يي، أنت...
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
Are you alright?
هل انت بخير؟
Stop worrying about other matters.
توقف عن القلق بشأن أمور أخرى.
Focus on recovering first.
ركز على التعافي أولاً.
Last night, I dispatched people to handle the aftermath.
لقد أرسلت الليلة الماضية أشخاصًا للتعامل مع العواقب.
In the eyes of nobility,
في نظر النبلاء،
someone like me
شخص مثلي
doesn't even deserve
لا يستحق حتى
a coffin when dead.
نعش عندما مات.
Whether you deserve it or not has nothing to do with others.
سواء كنت تستحق ذلك أم لا، فهذا ليس له علاقة بالآخرين.
But since they treat human life as nothing,
ولكن بما أنهم يعاملون الحياة البشرية وكأنها لا شيء،
we must seek justice for the wrongfully killed.
علينا أن نسعى لتحقيق العدالة للذين قتلوا ظلماً.
Don't worry,
لا تقلق،
I'm tough to kill.
أنا صعب القتل.
As for your brother's death,
أما بالنسبة لموت أخيك،
I came too late. I'm sorry.
لقد أتيت متأخرًا جدًا. أنا آسف.
It was not your fault.
لم يكن خطؤك.
I...
أنا...
Let's exchange secrets.
دعونا نتبادل الأسرار.
I'll reveal my identity,
سأكشف عن هويتي
and you tell me yours.
وأنت تخبرني برأيك.
Lady Ye,
السيدة يي،
what do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
That letter was indeed sent by my brother,
لقد تم إرسال هذه الرسالة بالفعل من قبل أخي،
but it was a secret missive for Duke Xuan's heir.
لكنها كانت رسالة سرية إلى وريث الدوق شوان.
Yet now, it's in your hand.
ولكن الآن الأمر بين يديك.
Either you serve the Young Lord,
إما أن تخدم اللورد الشاب،
or
أو
you're the enemy who intercepted it.
أنت العدو الذي اعترضه.
Lady Ye.
السيدة يي.
Listen.
يستمع.
The Inner Bureau is under the Royal Bureau.
المكتب الداخلي يتبع للمكتب الملكي.
By ancestral law, it answers to the Emperor alone,
بموجب القانون القديم، فهو يخضع للإمبراطور وحده،
immune to external oversight.
محصنة ضد الرقابة الخارجية.
I serve the royal family.
أنا أخدم العائلة المالكة.
That letter is in my hands.
هذه الرسالة بين يدي.
Naturally, there's a reason for it.
بطبيعة الحال، هناك سبب لذلك.
But I can tell you
ولكن يمكنني أن أخبرك
I
أنا
am not the Young Lord's enemy.
أنا لست عدوًا للسيد الشاب.
I trust you.
أنا أثق بك.
You...
أنت...
I'm the daughter of Postmaster Sang Kui from Duting Station.
أنا ابنة مدير مكتب البريد سانغ كوي من محطة دوتينغ.
My lord, please redress my family's injustice.
سيدي، من فضلك أصلح ظلم عائلتي.
Get up.
استيقظ.
I knew what you just said
لقد عرفت ما قلته للتو
long ago.
منذ زمن طويل.
You knew?
هل عرفت؟
Then...
ثم...
Then why did you...
ثم لماذا فعلت...؟
Princess Anhe's death has always been suspicious.
لقد كانت وفاة الأميرة آنه دائمًا مثيرة للشكوك.
But your father truly was in charge of Duting Station.
لكن والدك كان حقا مسؤولا عن محطة دوتينغ.
So he can't escape accountability.
لذلك فهو لا يستطيع الهروب من المساءلة.
Unless we find the real killer.
ما لم نجد القاتل الحقيقي.
My lord,
سيدي،
Master Lu is here asking about Lady Ye again.
السيد لو هنا يسأل عن السيدة يي مرة أخرى.
Are you that eager to see him?
هل أنت متشوق لرؤيته؟
Because I want to know who killed my parents
لأنني أريد أن أعرف من قتل والدي
and my brother.
وأخي.
That's exactly why
هذا هو السبب بالضبط
we can't let them know
لا يمكننا أن نخبرهم بذلك
we've returned.
لقد عدنا.
Listen to me. Rest here for a few days.
استمع لي. استرح هنا لبضعة أيام.
I'll keep investigating,
سأستمر في التحقيق،
seek justice for you,
اطلب العدالة من أجلك،
and bring Jin back.
وأعيد جين.
You'll both be free from the Lu family for good.
سوف يتم تحريركما من عائلة لو إلى الأبد.
(Prefect's Mansion)
(قصر الحاكم)
(Verses, wine, and arms breed new burdens. Plum as wife, crane as son, all past karma.)
(الأبيات، والنبيذ، والأسلحة تولد أعباء جديدة. البرقوق كزوجة، والكركي كابن، كل ذلك كارما الماضي.)
Verses, wine, and arms breed new burdens.
الآيات، والخمر، والأسلحة تولد أعباءً جديدة.
Plum as wife, crane as son, all past karma.
البرقوق كزوجة، والكركي كإبن، كل ذلك كارما الماضي.
My lord.
سيدي.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
Those pirates botched the job.
لقد أفسد هؤلاء القراصنة المهمة.
Shen Que has come back again.
لقد عاد شين كيو مرة أخرى.
Let him be.
دعوه يكون.
Officials and citizens in Ningzhou has always stood united.
لقد وقف المسؤولون والمواطنون في نينغتشو دائمًا متحدين.
He's just a lowly Governor-General.
إنه مجرد حاكم عام متواضع.
Can he really overturn our entire system?
هل يستطيع حقًا قلب نظامنا بأكمله؟
My lord,
سيدي،
I remember you never applied medicine for minor wounds like this.
أتذكر أنك لم تستخدم الدواء أبدًا لجروح بسيطة مثل هذه.
But now, you...
ولكن الآن أنت...
Stop all that nonsense.
اوقف كل هذا الهراء.
Wait...
انتظر...
- Apply the medicine. - Out.
- ضع الدواء. - خارج.
- Get out! Hurry.
- اخرج! بسرعة.
Apply the medicine.
استخدم الدواء.
It heals without the medicine? Am I a miracle physician?
هل يشفي بدون دواء؟ هل أنا طبيب معجزة؟
Lord Gao.
اللورد جاو.
Well, I see.
حسنا، أرى.
Lady Ye, you're here.
سيدة يي، أنت هنا.
Lord Shen is inside.
اللورد شين في الداخل.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
My lord,
سيدي،
you want me here for the Young Lord's matter, right?
تريدني هنا من أجل مسألة اللورد الشاب، أليس كذلك؟
I'll turn my back on you. As for the Young Lord,
سأدير ظهري لك. أما بالنسبة للسيد الشاب،
I think we should...
أعتقد أننا يجب أن...
Why does my wound hurt so much?
لماذا جرحي يؤلمني كثيرا؟
Could it be infected or something?
هل يمكن أن يكون مصابًا أو شيء من هذا القبيل؟
Never mind. Let me help you apply the medicine.
لا بأس، دعني أساعدك في وضع الدواء.
Okay.
تمام.
Your help is appreciated.
نحن نقدر مساعدتك.
You needn't trouble yourself like this.
لا داعي لأن تزعج نفسك بهذا الشكل.
It's okay. It will be easier this way.
لا بأس، سيكون الأمر أسهل بهذه الطريقة.
I won't look if that's better.
لن أنظر إذا كان هذا أفضل.
No. Even if you won't look, I need to look...
لا. حتى لو لم تنظر، فأنا بحاجة إلى النظر...
Who's been applying medicine for you all these years?
من كان يطبق عليك الطب كل هذه السنوات؟
Well... I grew accustomed to the battlefield.
حسنًا... لقد اعتدت على ساحة المعركة.
Such minor wounds aren't worth fussing over.
مثل هذه الجروح البسيطة لا تستحق الاهتمام بها.
It feels m-much better.
أشعر أنني أفضل بكثير.
How strange.
كم هو غريب.
I have something for you.
عندي لك شيئا.
(The Lu family poisoning case in Ningzhou 18 years ago)
(قضية تسمم عائلة لو في نينغتشو قبل 18 عامًا)
This letter...
هذه الرسالة...
Normally, I should let you keep this as a memento.
عادةً، يجب أن أسمح لك بالاحتفاظ بهذا كتذكار.
But under current circumstances,
ولكن في ظل الظروف الحالية،
it's best burned.
من الأفضل حرقها.
Mu kept such a heavy secret
لقد احتفظ مو بسر ثقيل جدًا
for me for so many years.
بالنسبة لي لسنوات عديدة.
Turns out
اتضح
they let me live
لقد سمحوا لي بالعيش
only to hook him.
فقط لربطه.
How much do you remember from back then?
كم تتذكر من ذلك الوقت؟
I was young.
لقد كنت صغيرا.
I only remember
انا فقط أتذكر
a beautiful lady came to the station.
جاءت سيدة جميلة إلى المحطة.
She treated us so kindly.
لقد تعاملت معنا بلطف شديد.
Come on.
تعال.
Eat well,
تناول الطعام جيدا
so you can grow up strong.
لكي تتمكن من النمو بقوة.
It's so delicious.
إنه لذيذ جداً.
Make a guess. Is it a boy or girl in my belly?
خمن. هل في بطني ولد أم بنت؟
I think it's a girl.
أعتقد أنها فتاة.
What do you think, Sangye?
ماذا تعتقد، سانجي؟
I want to hear it.
أريد أن أسمعه.
Come on.
تعال.
He's kicking me.
إنه يركلني.
It must be a boy.
لا بد أن يكون صبيًا.
Will you name him then?
هل ستسميه إذن؟
My father taught me a poem.
لقد علمني والدي قصيدة.
Silver saddle illuminates white steed, galloping swift as meteors speed.
سرج فضي يضيء حصانًا أبيضًا يركض بسرعة مثل سرعة النيازك.
Let's name him Yin Ruxing. How's that?
لنسمِّه ين روشينغ. ما رأيك؟
Yin Ruxing, the wandering knight.
ين روكسينج، الفارس المتجول.
Okay.
تمام.
So you named the Young Lord?
فهل أطلقت على هذا الشاب هذا الاسم؟
♪Grind flesh between grit and stone♪
???طحن اللحم بين الحصى والحجر؟؟؟
♪Sink into pain, only then are pearls born♪
???الغرق في الألم، حينها فقط تولد اللآلئ؟؟؟
♪Wait until abyssal darkness stains every inch of skin♪
???انتظر حتى يلطخ الظلام السحيق كل بوصة من الجلد ???
♪Then comes the time to chase the dawn♪
???ثم يأتي الوقت لمطاردة الفجر؟؟؟
♪I'll sweep through dusty sands♪
???سوف أقوم بالمسح عبر الرمال المليئة بالغبار؟؟؟
♪Passing wind♪
???ريح عابرة؟؟؟
♪Entwine my hair in dance♪
???تشابك شعري في الرقص؟؟؟
♪I'll lean into his embrace♪
???سوف أستند إلى حضنه؟؟؟
♪Wade through deep seas♪
???خوض البحار العميقة؟؟؟
♪Bathing in affection♪
???الاستحمام في المودة؟؟؟
♪Condensing into rain♪
???تتكاثف إلى مطر؟؟؟
♪Who cast a frantic, lingering glance♪
???من الذي ألقى نظرة محمومة ومتأخرة؟
♪Carrying endless tenderness♪
???تحمل حنانًا لا نهاية له؟؟؟
♪Gazing through eons of moonlit winds♪
???التحديق عبر عصور من الرياح المضاءة بالقمر؟؟؟
♪Turn tears to pearls and cradle them within♪
???تحويل الدموع إلى لؤلؤ وضمها إلى داخلها؟؟؟
♪Henceforth we walk the mortal realm♪
???من الآن فصاعدا نسير في عالم البشر؟؟؟
♪Across vast mountains and rivers♪
???عبر الجبال والأنهار الشاسعة؟؟؟
♪I'll sweep through dusty sands♪
???سوف أقوم بالمسح عبر الرمال المليئة بالغبار؟؟؟
♪Passing wind♪
???ريح عابرة؟؟؟
♪Entwine my hair in dance♪
???تشابك شعري في الرقص؟؟؟
♪I'll lean into his embrace♪
???سوف أستند إلى حضنه؟؟؟
♪Wade through deep seas♪
???خوض البحار العميقة؟؟؟
♪Bathing in affection♪
???الاستحمام في المودة؟؟؟
♪Condensing into rain♪
???تتكاثف إلى مطر؟؟؟